Aron Teh

★ aronteh.com **⑤** github.com/Ellipsoul **in** linkedin.com/in/aronteh **☒** aronteh.chess@gmail.com

I taught myself to code as a complete beginner and secured a full time software engineer position in less than 4 months. Experienced and confident in full-stack web development, with recent interest in machine learning.

Professional Experience

Amazon 🛮

Software Development Engineer

Nov 2022 - present | United Kingdom

- Delivered a high priority, time-constrained project spanning multiple teams across the Living Room Platform organisation, facilitating a Prime Video launch in 8 new countries and expected to acquire several million new Prime customers.
- Communicated, mitigated and resolved multiple high severity incidents and alerts during regular on-call rotations.
- Onboarded and welcomed two new engineers during eighth week of tenure in absence of experienced team members.
- Developed efficient, scalable and robustly-tested API features with complex expectations and dependencies.
- Contributed to development of a universally compatible backend framework for current and future Living Room teams.

THG 7

Sep 2021 - Oct 2022 | United Kingdom

Software Engineer

- Developed and maintained an Angular component library and Java backend to be used by multiple internal teams.
- Collaborated effectively with UX designers to build Angular UIs for an internal content management system.

{} Programming Languages

HTML | CSS (Sass, Less) | JavaScript | Typescript | Python | SQL | Java | MATLAB | Dart | Rust | R

Skills and Technologies

React (v18) | Next.js (v13) | Angular | Firebase (v9) | Git | Tailwind | npm | Yarn | webpack | REST Testing (Unit, Integrated, E2E) | Jest | Cypress | Puppeteer | Axios | RxJS | AWS | Continuous Integration Continuous Deployment | Bash | Docker | Kubernetes | Scrum | Kanban | Flask | GraphQL | Flutter Vue | Svelte | Gradle | Spring | Lerna | Vercel | PyTorch | Project Planning | Mathematics | Statistics

Technical Personal Projects

SkyStory 2

Angular, Firebase (Firestore, Authentication, Hosting), Tailwind, Angular Material, Axios, RxJS, REST API, PWA

- Dynamically themed and responsive progressive web application (PWA) where users can guery live and forecasted weather information, utilising a third-party REST API service to retrieve global weather data.
- Integrated Firebase authentication and Firestore database automatically saves queries for authenticated users.

NanoNote 🖪

Angular, Firebase (Firestore, Authentication, Hosting), Tailwind, Angular Material

- Lightweight and responsive web application for managing simple notes, secured with Firebase authentication.
- Users can create, manage, update, sort and categorise unlimited notes in an intuitive, minimalistic and dual-themed UI.

TurboFile 🖪

React (Next.js), Firebase (Storage, Authentication), Tailwind, Material UI, Jest, Puppeteer, Vercel Hosting

- Responsive and multi-themed web application where users can upload and share files within seconds.
- Additional features to view, download and manage uploaded files are unlocked for users authenticated with Google.

Education

Imperial College London

2017 - 2021 | London, United Kingdom

Aeronautical Engineering (MEng, Master of Engineering)

Master's Thesis : Sparse conic optimisation parallel solver with the Alternating Direction Method of Multipliers. Notable Modules: High Performance Computing, Mathematics, Numerical Analysis, Optimisation, Control Systems.

Languages

English (Native Proficiency) | Chinese (Native Proficiency) | Cantonese (Beginner)

Interests

Chess (Youngest ever Malaysia National Chess Champion (2013), FIDE Master (Lifetime International Title), World Chess Olympiad Participant (Norway 2014), President of Imperial College London Chess Club (2018-2019), Private Teacher)